Michael Cano

Email: jmburagay@protonmail.com

Summary

I am a Full-Stack senior web developer in Python, Django and AngularJS. I have been working on, - Python - Django - MySQL - PostgreSQL - AngularJS - Jquery - Javascript - HTML - CSS - Selenium testing framework integration - Social network API integration - Rest API integration - Payment gateway integration - Writing automation scripts for OPS - Charts integration - Git/Bitbucket/Svn - Site Deployment and maintenance - Writing scripts to monitor services in server - Continuous Integration(CI) My role is involved in complete end-end development and management of website development projects and I am expecting opportunities to build websites with well standards.

C/C++ software developer offering more than four years of full life cycle experience including planning and assessment, requirements definition, features and functionality design and development, coding, testing, QA, implementation, product and infrastructure enhancements and maintenance. An expert in object-oriented design and analysis with a history of building unique and original products and solutions through intuitive problem-solving and creativity.

Strong proficiency in JavaScript, including DOM manipulation and the JavaScript object model;

- Thorough understanding and expertise at React.js and its core principles
- Experience with popular React.js workflows (such as Flux or Redux)
- Familiarity with EcmaScript
- Prior experience with data structure libraries
- Familiarity with RESTful APIs
- Knowledge of advanced level programming in C/C++ including thread synchronization multithreading, multi processing, concurrency and TCP/IP Socket Programming.
- Developed dozens of applications for inventory maintenance, vendor information and order processing which increased efficiencies and reduced operating costs 11 percent.
- Reduced support costs 22 percent by creating hundreds of enhancements for existing apps running on Windows and UNIX platforms. Tactics included troubleshooting, root cause analysis, bug fixing and decreasing the codebase 25 percent.
- Increased e-commerce revenues 3 percent by fine tuning 16 applications involved in the fulfillment of website orders.

• Proficient in Web technologies: HTML, CSS, PHP and Java

SKILLS

- Github, Jira, Bitbucket git AWS APIs:
- google maps, youtube API, facebook, etc.
- Setup and customizing Wordpress Themes;
- I specialize in Website Wordpress Performance Optimization;
- Over 6 years experience in WordPress Development;
- Building functional, beautiful and responsive Wordpress websites;
- Wordpress upkeep, edits, troubleshooting;
- Python Django
- MySQL Administration PostgreSQL Administration
- React, Redux, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, TypeScript
- Design, prototype and develop the web application or API by using the latest technologies and approaches.
- Setup your cloud infrastructure with Azure, AWS or Google Cloud using the correct tools depending on your requirements and business needs.
- Configure proper logging and performance monitoring tools to catch any application related issues or errors, before it could affect your business.
- Optimize new versions delivery and to configure continuous integration to eliminate the possible human errors and to reduce maintenance costs.
- Enhance the performance or to resolve bugs or any other issues in existing web application.
- Implement the API and to connect the frontend part by using Angular or React frameworks.

EXPERIENCE

- C# 8 years
- C++ 8 years
- .NET Framework
- C# ASP.NET MVC
- Azure
- Angular React
- ASP.NET Core
- .NET Core
- TypeScript
- Python 8 years
- Django 3 years
- PHP 9 years
- NodeJS 8 years
- ReactJS 4 years
- AngularJS 4 years
- MySQL 8 years
- Java 8 years
- Springboot 5 years
- Agile 4 years

Education

BS Computer Science

AMA Computer College

WORK EXPERIENCE

TikTok Magic

August - November 2020

Full Stack Developer

- Created the entire system both frontend and backend
- Used NodeJS for some of the backend like searchinhg users and videos on Tiktok

Backdoor Navigator

Full Stack Developer

March - September 2020

- Worked on backend
- Fixed errors on frontend
- Implemented new features
- Used NodeJS for the backend of Backdoor Navigator a project of CritterMap Software. It's a web application for hikers and joggers to manage their routes on a map on a webpage. Heavy manipulation of MongoDB is implemented here.

EverydayEducate

January 2019 - February 2020 Full Stack Developer

- Worked on several websites using wordpress
- Woked on online stores using shopify
- Used NodeJS on one of the project for the backend.
- I have developed more than 10 websites using Python, Django, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Google DataStore, Jquery, Javascript and Css.
- I was leading two developers, one tester and one designer. Responsibilities:
 - Involved in Analysis and Design of the modules.
 - Creating models in backend.
 - Developed connections module.
 - Developed forum module
 - Integrated boxy script throughout the site.
 - Managed all front and backend forms using client side and server side validations using iquery and AJAX.
 - Developed code for managing files through AJAX in private notes module.
 - Developed code global search by context processor

FullStack Devs

December 2017 - October 2018

Sr. Developer & Project Manager

- deployed and maintained kiosks software of cryptocurrency ATMs all over the world
- Used React and worked on Frontend of a restaurant application where it has several systems like the ordering menu and the delivery rider system.
- Setting up Blockchain explorer for several clients, including Fenix Coin and Moore chain. This requires Node.Js server and Node.Js app to establish connection with wallet / full node and gather all information in Mongo so client can query through webUI

Jan 2016 – Feb 2017 Senior Web Developer

- Planned, designed, and built a variety of features for web based applications
- Worked collaboratively using git/github repository management and workflow
- Built uploaders and exporters, business reports, and PDF/CSV generators

Freelance Developer

February 2014 - 2015

Programmer

0

- Worked on many software for different clients including desktop applications and mobile apps
- Used React on Web app that is use by companies to track their drivers in Australia

PERSONAL PROJECTS

1. I created a big single page application with different types of entities like cars, jobs, customers, etc. I used React/Redux architecture, NodeJS, Express and MongoDB as a backend. The technological choice allowed to easily find another senior JavaScript developer in few months and made possible us to successfully work in tandem. My goal was to always keep the project extensible (even when we've got tens of screens) and up to date with the newest JavaScript libraries. S

 $\underline{\mathbf{w}}$. I reinvented the online JavaScript linter. It was an advanced version of jsonlint.com which includes features proposed by the development community: - Save/restore - Batch mode - Diff mode - Show # of bytes etc Data is stored at Amazon S3 storage; backend is powered by NodeJS and Express.S

h \mathbf{S} o S w t 1 e e X S t S t e Х